

I'm a web developer based in Portland, OR, who loves collaborating across teams to build creative, scalable, user-friendly products.

Currently focused on front-end development using React with Redux, but have also worked in all parts of the stack. I have startup experience, which has trained me to be adaptable to new technology, take risks, and move quickly.

My background in design and communications makes me a valuable asset to dev teams for UI/UX decisions and to articulate our work and process to others.

SKILLS

- » HTML & CSS
- » Javascript & ¡Query
- » React with Redux
- » SASS
- » Bootstrap
- » LAMP stack
- » Version Control (Git & Github)
- » WordPress
- » IDFs & Text Editors: Sublime Text, Atom, PhpStorm
- » Productivity & Agile: Slack, Jira, Confluence, Redmine
- » Photoshop & InDesign
- » A/B Testing (Optimizely)
- » Email Development & ESP management (Litmus. Constant Contact. MailChimp, SailThru)
- » Google Tag Manager & Google Analytics

EDUCATION

M.A., Virginia Tech (English)

Digital Humanities-focused coursework & thesis (HTML, TEI-markup)

Taught Freshman English for two years

B.A., University of Minnesota (Political Science & French Studies)

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer The Bouqs Company | Venice, CA | Nov. 2014-April 2016

Worked with a lean team at an ecommerce startup to develop a new, scalable consumer-facing web app in React with Redux, collaborating on component structure, data models, and interaction.

Developed end-to-end features in legacy Prestashop code base (an ecommerce LAMPstack app, CMS & CRM) for both the consumerand admin-facing sites.

Built modular components for all email retention and marketing campaigns, triggering drips via the CRM and training staff on how to create emails using new code snippets in Litmus.

Implemented third-party tracking tools via Google Tag Manager.

Built A/B and multivariate tests in Optimizely.

HTML, CSS & SASS Javascript (ES5 & ES6) React with Redux LAMP stack (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP) Photoshop Responsive Design GTM & Google Analytics Optimizely **Email Development** Litmus MailChimp & SailThru Git & Github Agile & Scrum with Jira **Jenkins AWS**

Communications Associate Levitt Foundation | Beverly Hills, CA September 2013-July 2014

Developed emails and maintained web content using a custom CMS and WordPress.

Collaborated with Levitt team to test new website usability and functionality.

Designed custom graphics for the web, print and online publications, ads, and campaigns.

Photoshop, Illustrator & InDesign HTML & CSS WordPress **Constant Contact** Google Analytics Social Media

Writer/Editor Virginia Tech | Blacksburg, VA | July 2011-July 2013

Managed communications and created brand identity for a multimillion dollar US government initiative.

Web content management in multiple CMSs.

HTMI Photoshop & InDesign Social Media Dreamweaver

Communications Assistant August 2006-July 2008

The Art Institute of Chicago | Chicago, IL

Handled communications for the encyclopedic museum's children's and family division.

Photoshop Web Content